Lois Gibbs Love Canal Papers MS063
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Lois Gibbs Love Canal Papers
1951 -- 2010
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Gibbs, Lois
MS063
37.9 Linear Feet 31 record cartons, 1 object box, and 1 oversize box.
Lois Gibbs is a former resident of Love Canal, co-founder of the Love Canal Homeowners Association, and co-founder of the Citizens' Clearinghouse for Hazardous Waste (later the Center for Health, Environment and Justice). Her papers document the Love Canal disaster and its aftermath, and include subject files, newspaper clippings, health studies, reports about the Love Canal site and its residents, and a small amount of audiovisual and ephemeral material.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stephen Lester 2011-2017; accession numbers 2012.023, 2015.013, and 2017.042.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into five series: Subject files; Newspaper clippings; Health studies; Publications and reports; and Awards, audiovisual materials, and ephemera. Received order has largely been maintained by the processing archivists.
Biographical / Historical
Lois Gibbs (born 1951) is an environmental activist who formed the Love Canal Homeowners Association after discovering that her entire neighborhood of Love Canal, Niagara Falls, New York, had been built on a toxic waste dump. The organization succeeded against strong opposition by local, state, and federal government agencies, and Occidental Petroleum, and President Carter issued an Emergency Declaration in October 1980 to get 833 families evacuated and Love Canal cleaned up. Lois Gibbs and the association were instrumental in the establishment of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency's Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act, or Superfund. In 1980, Gibbs founded the Citizens' Clearinghouse for Hazardous Waste, later renamed the Center for Health, Environment and Justice, and served as its executive director. She has published about Love Canal and was the subject of the TV movie, 'Lois Gibbs: the Love Canal Story.' Gibbs received honorary doctorates from the State University of New York; Cortland College; Haverford College; Green Mountain College; Medaille College; and Tufts University. She has also received numerous awards, including the 1990 Goldman Environmental Prize and the 1998 Heinz Award. She was nominated for the Nobel Peace Prize in 2003. Gibbs sits on numerous Boards and Advisory Committees, and lives in Falls Church, Virginia with her husband, Stephen Lester.
Custodial History
Boxes 1 through 4 of series one contain legacy files which were transferred to DCA in the 1990s. The remainder of the collection was donated by Stephen Lester in three accessions, 2011-2017.
Related Materials
Center for Health, Environment, and Justice Records, 1942-2016. Tufts University. Digital Collections and Archives. Medford, MA.
Scope and Contents
The Lois Gibbs Love Canal papers contain materials primarily about the Love Canal disaster and its aftermath. The collection consists of correspondence; newspaper clippings; health studies; published material; presentations; reports; subject files; and a small amount of audiovisual materials. Of particular interest are subject files from the Love Canal Homeowners Association (LCHA), which Gibbs founded with other Love Canal residents, and a set of materials that Gibbs gathered together as a Women's Activist kit to highlight women in activism and inspire others to organize.
This collection largely documents efforts to relocate Love Canal community members; environmental and health studies conducted on the Love Canal site and its residents; clean-up, construction, and other remedial actions taken at Love Canal; the Love Canal Habitability Study; the resettlement of Love Canal; and the activities of the Love Canal Medical Fund (LCMF).
Significant individuals in this collection include David Axelrod, Commissioner of the New York State Department of Health; Stephen Lester, Clement Associates, Inc. staff scientist and member of the Love Canal Medical Fund Board of Directors; and Dr. Beverly Paigen, Roswell Park Memorial Institute scientist. Other notable entities include the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Hooker Chemical Company, New York State Department of Health, Occidental Chemical Corporation, and the Center for Disease Control and Prevention. The bulk of the materials in this collection date from 1978-1982.
Lois Gibbs; Love Canal, NY; Environmental history; Social justice
- Subject files, circa 1951 -- 2007; MS063.001; 19.2 Linear Feet 16 record cartons
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of subject files compiled primarily by Lois Gibbs and Stephen Lester pertaining to the Love Canal disaster and its aftermath. Materials include correspondence; environmental and health data; newsletters; newspaper clippings; press releases; reports, such as soil reports; safety plans; testimonies before different United States legislative subcommittees; and other documents. The bulk of the material is dated from 1978-1982.
  This series documents the activities of Lois Gibbs and the Love Canal Homeowners Association (LCHA), including Gibbs' correspondence with government personnel; construction at the Love Canal site; medical, scientific, and political investigations of both Love Canal and its residents; fundraising efforts to help displaced Love Canal residents; the Love Canal Revitalization Agency; the Love Canal Habitabilty Study; and the resettlement of Love Canal.
  Several folders in this series focus on other organizations, such as the Environmental Support Center, a pro-environmental organization which assisted in the development of grassroots environmentalist groups via the provision of training, resources, and funding; and the Legal Environmental Assistance Foundation (LEAF), a legal and pro-environmental watchdog organization. Gibbs served on the board of directors for both organizations.
  Significant individuals in this series include government officials and scientists, including David Axelrod, Tom Bartosiewicz, Jimmy Carter, Mario Cuomo, Robert Flacke, William Hennessy, Stephen Lester, Adeline Levine, and Beverly Paigen. Other notable entities include the Center for Disease Control (CDC), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Hooker Chemical Company, Housing and Urban Development (HUD), New York State Department of Health (DOH), and Occidental Chemical Corporation.
  There are a significant number of more recent archival materials about the Love Canal Medical Fund (LCMF) — primarily annual reports, correspondence, financial records, medical benefit plans, meeting minutes, and newsletters — that document the activities of this organization and its board of directors. Most of these materials are closed for 75 years.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in received order.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
  - Accidents - On Site, 1979; MS063.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Open for research.
  - Action Committee, 1979; MS063.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Ad - Full page, 1979; MS063.001.001.00003 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 9, Box 1)
  - Addresses, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Air Data, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Air Samples, 1979; MS063.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Army Dumping, 1980; MS063.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Assoc. Annual Reports, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    Love Canal Homeowners Association
  - Assoc. By Laws and Structure, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Assoc - Dear Friend Tri-Fold, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Association Newsletters, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Awards, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Axelrod, Commissioner (DOH), 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Axelrod Memos Recieved, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Axelrod Memos Sent Out, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Stephen Barron - Nerve Study, 1980; MS063.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Senator Tom Bartosiewicz, 1980; MS063.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - BEU Coverup, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Bloody-Run Dump, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Board of Director, 1979 -- 1981; MS063.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Board of Education, 1979; MS063.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Mike Brown's Cancer $ Risks, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - CAG - Air Risk Analysis, 1979; MS063.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Calspan Report, 1977; MS063.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Canal Residents Relocated List 5/81, 1981; MS063.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
    75 years from date of creation.
  - Govenor Carey, 1982 -- 1987; MS063.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - CECOS - Hearing, 1980; MS063.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - CDC Protocols, 1980 -- 1981; MS063.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - CDC- Study and Correspondence, 1980; MS063.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - CDC and UB Letters, 1980; MS063.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - CDC/UB Medical Center, 1980 -- 1981; MS063.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Certification of Incorp. LCHA, 1980; MS063.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Certification Program and Motel Information, 1979; MS063.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Chemicals and Health Study, 1979; MS063.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Chemicals Identified at Canal, 1979; MS063.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Chromosome Study, 1980; MS063.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Chronological Reports Events and Newspapers, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Chronology, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - Cigarette Study - Axelrod's Preg Risks, 1979; MS063.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - City Dept., 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - City Directory, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - Cleveland Clinic - Taylor, 1979; MS063.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Comptroller, 1979; MS063.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Conferences, 1980; MS063.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Conservation Foundation ReRA Regs CEQ Report, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Construction Plans, 1978; MS063.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Costle, Douglas - EPA, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Cuddy, Michael, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Senator Daly - State, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Day Care Love Canal Study, 1979; MS063.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Deeds, 1951 -- 1979; MS063.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Dept. of Health Health Study Report, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - DEURO Drive - Petition, MS063.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Dioxin Data, 1978; MS063.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Doctors Statements, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Draft changes, 1980; MS063.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Ebert, Vincent, 1978 -- 1981; MS063.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Ecumenical Task Force, 1979 -- 1981; MS063.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Environmental Defense Fund, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - EPA Demo Grant, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Federal Form, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Federal Laws and Regulations, 1976 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Federal travel Vouchers and Political Letters, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - 54 families Health Questionaires, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Flacke, Commissioner Robert, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Fonda and Hayden, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Thomas Frey, 1978; MS063.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Fund Raising - letters sent out, 1979; MS063.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Fund Raising Meeting, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Gibbs, Lois (Love Canal), 1980 -- 1982; MS063.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Grant Proposals, 1980 -- 1982; MS063.001.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - Growth and Maturation, 1983; MS063.001.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Glenn Haughie, 1978; MS063.001.002.00032 (Box 2)
  - Hazardous Materials Intelligence Report, 1980; MS063.001.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - Health Data, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00034 (Box 2)
  - Health, Education, Welfare, 1979; MS063.001.002.00035 (Box 2)
  - Health Questionaires, MS063.001.002.00036 (Box 2)
  - Health Questionaires NYS - CDC - LCHA, MS063.001.002.00037 (Box 2)
  - HEDGE Survey, 1979; MS063.001.002.00038 (Box 2)
  - W.C. Hennessy, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00039 (Box 2)
  - Hooker Chemical, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.002.00040 (Box 2)
  - Hooker and OCC, 1952 -- 1981; MS063.001.002.00041 (Box 2)
  - HUD, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Interagency Task Force on Hazardous Waste, 1979; MS063.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Interim Reports (DOH), 1979; MS063.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Senator Javits, 1980; MS063.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Dr. William Jusko, 1980; MS063.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Edward Kennedy, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Jon Kenny, 1979; MS063.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Luella Kenny, 1979; MS063.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Congressman LaFalce, 1978 -- 1982; MS063.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Laundry Lists, MS063.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Lewis, Thomas, 1980 -- 1981; MS063.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Rich Lippes, 1978 -- 1981; MS063.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Liver Data - State's, 1978; MS063.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - LCHA, 1981; MS063.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Melbreth's Report, 1981; MS063.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Membership list, 1981; MS063.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Senator Moynihan, 1978 -- 1981; MS063.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Murphy, Matt - Assembly, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - National Health Insurance, 1979; MS063.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - New landfill N.7. Porter Rd., 1981; MS063.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - News Articles of Interest, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Niagra County, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - 93rd St., 1968 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Minority Leader OHRENSTEIN, 1979; MS063.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Originals for Zeroxing, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Outside Interests, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Paigen Blood and Urine tests, 1979 -- 1981; MS063.001.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - David Parry - Wm. T Love History, 1976; MS063.001.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Photos of Canal and Neighborhood, 1979; MS063.001.003.00030 (Box 3)
    - Empty chairs in a school hallway with worker in background, 1979; MS063.001.003.00030.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 185.72 Megabytes
      Black and white photograph of a row of empty chairs blocking a hallway in the school at Love Canal with a worker in the background
    - Worker Cleaning up school at Love Canal, 1979; MS063.001.003.00030.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 176.34 Megabytes
      Black and white photograph of a worker cleaning up the school at Love Canal
  - Poems, 1980; MS063.001.003.00031 (Box 3)
  - Political Letters, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00032 (Box 3)
  - Political Newsletters, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00033 (Box 3)
  - Press Statements, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00034 (Box 3)
  - Rall, David - NIEHS, 1979; MS063.001.003.00035 (Box 3)
  - RECRA - Samples Research, 1979; MS063.001.003.00036 (Box 3)
  - Red Cross, 1980; MS063.001.003.00037 (Box 3)
  - Renter's Association, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00038 (Box 3)
  - Report to Governor, 1979 -- 1981; MS063.001.003.00039 (Box 3)
  - Revitalization Committee, 1980 -- 1983; MS063.001.003.00040 (Box 3)
  - Rosso, Alan, MS063.001.003.00041 (Box 3)
  - 609... and counting nuclear waste sites, 1980; MS063.001.003.00042 (Box 3)
  - Slack, Joe - Dec, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.003.00043 (Box 3)
  - State Health Form, 1978; MS063.001.003.00044 (Box 3)
  - Summary Report, 1979; MS063.001.003.00045 (Box 3)
  - Superfund, 1980; MS063.001.003.00046 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Vianna, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.003.00047 (Box 3)
  - Wet areas north of Colvin, MS063.001.003.00048 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Robert Whalen, 1978; MS063.001.003.00049 (Box 3)
  - 1: Table of Contents, 1978; MS063.001.003.00050 (Box 3)
  - 2: Executive Summary, 1978; MS063.001.003.00051 (Box 3)
  - 3: Brief History of Love Canal site, 1978; MS063.001.003.00052 (Box 3)
  - 4: Calspan Report, 1978; MS063.001.003.00053 (Box 3)
  - 5: Department of Environmental Conservation Assessment of Hazardous Waste Management Concerns, 1978; MS063.001.003.00054 (Box 3)
  - 6: Commissioner of Health's Action to abate the Hazard and the local response, 1978; MS063.001.003.00055 (Box 3)
  - 7: Research Triangle Institute Report on Analysis of Air Samples in Basements of Homes Adjacent to the Love Canal Site, 1978; MS063.001.003.00056 (Box 3)
  - 8: Resarch Triangle Institute Report "Improvement of Methodologies for the Collection and Analysis of Carcinogenic Vapors", 1978; MS063.001.003.00057 (Box 3)
  - 9: "Site Study and Preliminary Design of A Groundwater Pollution Abatement plan" Conestoga-Rovers and Associates, 1978; MS063.001.003.00058 (Box 3)
  - 10: Assessment of Potential Health Hazardous Associated with levels identified by Research Triangle Institute, 1978; MS063.001.003.00059 (Box 3)
  - 11: Informational Meetings Held in Niagra Falls For Love Canal residents, 1978; MS063.001.003.00060 (Box 3)
  - Efforts by the EPA to Identify Agents Likely to be Present in the Love Canal, 1978; MS063.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Meeting Held in Albany to Assess Roundtable Information and Provide Recommendations, 1978; MS063.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - "Phase I Pollution Abatement Plan - Upper Groundwater Regime," Conestoga-Rovers and Associates, 1978; MS063.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Critique of Conestoga-Rovers Abatement Plan, 1978; MS063.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Air Sampling data from Landfill Site and Basement of Homes, 1978; MS063.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - A Special Problem: The Voorhees Residence, 1978; MS063.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Data from Epidemiologic Studies of Individuals Residing Directly Adjacent to Landfill Site, 1978; MS063.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Public Health Time Bomb: A Special Report, 1978; MS063.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - 33: News Clips and Releases: 9/78-3/79, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - 34: Love Canal Task force A Brief Chronology Proposed legislation, 1979; MS063.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - 35: Commissioner of Health Orders, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - 36: Niagra County Health Deparment: A Brief Chronology, 1978; MS063.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - 37: Daily Reports - On Site Office, Love Canal Task Force, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - 38: Application and Correspondence with the Federal Disaster Assistance Agency, 1978; MS063.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - 39: Litigation, 1978; MS063.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - 40: United Way of Niagra: Proposed Contract, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - 41: Interagency Task Force on Hazardous Wastes and the Hooker Chemical Company, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - 42: Hyde Park Landfill, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - 43: City of Niagra Falls Water Supply and the "S" Chemical Landfill Site, 1978; MS063.001.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - 44: Report of Air photos fo 102nd Street Landfill, 1979; MS063.001.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - 45: Report on Army Investigation: Love Canal, 1978; MS063.001.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - 46: Fred C. Hart Report on Second phase of study, 1978; MS063.001.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - 47: Groundwater Hydrology and Soil Contaminants at the Love Canal, 1978; MS063.001.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - 48: Radiological Surveys at the Love Canal, 1978; MS063.001.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - 49: USEPA Study of Storm Sewers at Love Canal, 1978; MS063.001.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - 50: Summary of Air, Soil, and Water Studies: Division of Labratories and Research, 1978; MS063.001.004.00026 (Box 4)
  - 51: The Tolli Residence and Storm Sewer Flooding, 1978; MS063.001.004.00027 (Box 4)
  - 52: Infrared Arial Surveillance of 39 Landfills - a proposal, 1978; MS063.001.004.00028 (Box 4)
  - 53: The Owens' Study: Preliminary Soil Report, 1978; MS063.001.004.00029 (Box 4)
  - 54: Dioxin Studies, 1978; MS063.001.004.00030 (Box 4)
  - 55: Analysis of Treated Leachate at the Love Canal, 1978; MS063.001.004.00031 (Box 4)
  - 57: Liver Function Studies, 1978; MS063.001.004.00032 (Box 4)
  - 58: Summary of Review of Medical Records, 1978; MS063.001.004.00033 (Box 4)
  - 59: Research Triangle, Inc Studies - Preliminary Findings, 1978; MS063.001.004.00034 (Box 4)
  - 62: EPA Grant Application for Demonstration Project, 1978; MS063.001.004.00035 (Box 4)
  - 63: Botanical and Animal Studies: A Preliminary Report, 1978; MS063.001.004.00036 (Box 4)
  - 64: Love Canal Land Use Committee, 1979; MS063.001.004.00037 (Box 4)
  - 65: Federal Agency Participation in Health and Environmental Investigations, 1978; MS063.001.004.00038 (Box 4)
  - Names, Addresses, and Medical Conditions, M-R, 1978; MS063.001.004.00039 (Box 4)
  - Names, Addresses, and Medical Conditions, S-Z, 1978; MS063.001.004.00040 (Box 4)
  - Safety plans, circa 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.005.00001; 2 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - William Sanjour and Hugh Kaufman, circa 1980; MS063.001.005.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Interviews, circa 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.005.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Love Canal Homeowners Association Speakers Committee, circa 1979; MS063.001.005.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lois Gibbs's speeches and notes, circa 1980; MS063.001.005.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Speaker's Committee, 1979; MS063.001.005.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Superfund, 1981; MS063.001.005.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bills - state, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.005.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Steve Lester memos, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.005.00009; 2 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Earth Dimensions, Inc. and Don Owens, 1979; MS063.001.005.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Steve Lester's daily reports, 1978 -- 1979; MS063.001.005.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - EPA status report, 1980; MS063.001.005.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Testimonies, circa 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.005.00013; 2 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
  - Sherman, Janette M.D., 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.005.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - State informational bulletins, circa 1978 -- 1981; MS063.001.005.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Status reports - state, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.005.00016; 2 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
  - Exhibits, circa 1978; MS063.001.005.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 21)
    75 years from the date of creation.
  - Telegrams, circa 1978 -- 1981; MS063.001.006.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Tax relief, 1979; MS063.001.006.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - United Nations, circa 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.006.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - United Way - Maloney, circa 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.006.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Union lists, circa 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.006.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - President Carter and agreement, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.006.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - White House letters, 1979 -- 1980; MS063.001.006.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Washington - correspondence sent out and received, 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.006.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Town of Wheatfield, 1979; MS063.001.006.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Weather reports - Niagara Falls, circa 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.006.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Addie Levine, circa 1978 -- 1982; MS063.001.006.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letters sent out, circa 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.006.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letters received, circa 1978 -- 1980; MS063.001.006.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 13)